White Oleander is a drama film directed by Peter Kosminsky.
A teenager journeys through a series of foster homes after her
mother goes to prison for committing a crime of passion.
Astrid Magnussen, played by Alison Lohman.
Ingrid Magnussen, played by Michelle Pfeiffer.
Claire Richards, played by Renée Zellweger.
Starr, played by Robin Wright.
Ray, played by Cole Hauser.
Paramedic, played by Melissa McCarthy.
White Oleander is a 2002 American drama film directed by Peter Kosminsky.
The film stars Alison Lohman in the central role of Astrid Magnussen and Michelle Pfeiffer as her
manipulative mother, Ingrid, with Robin Wright, Noah Wyle, and Renée Zellweger in supporting roles.
The screenplay was adapted from Janet Fitch's 1999 novel White Oleander,
which was selected for Oprah's Book Club in May 1999.
The film explores themes of prison, loss of loved one,
poison, foster parents, women's prison.
The tone is emotional.